# Bruno P. Kinoshita

(021) 104 2131 • ☑ kinow@apache.org • ② https://kinoshita.eti.br
in brunopkinoshita • У kinow • ⑤ kinow

Brazilian-New Zealander, married, 36 years old, non-smoker

In the past seventeen years have worked in different industries including telecommunications, banking, credit, retail, insurance, research, government, and start-ups. Occupied different positions such as programmer, quality engineer, devops, architect, full stack developer, big data engineer, and frontend developer.

I am fluent in English and Portuguese. I have an intermediate level of Spanish, and basic of Japanese and French. Attended Te Reo Maori beginner classes to learn basic vocabulary and pronunciation.

#### Skills

Languages Java, Python, PHP, R, C/C++, CSS, HTML, JavaScript, Shell, Perl, SQL Frameworks Node.js, NumPy, Pandas, Spark, Spring, SpringBoot, Struts, Hadoop, Tornado,

Laravel

Systems Linux, OSX, Windows

Other Open Source, GIS, Semantic Web, Linked Data, Natural Language Processing

#### **Achievements**

o GSoC Mentor, Jenkins Machine Learning Plug-in	March 2020, to September 2020
o Invited to become an Apache Software Foundation Member	March 2018
o Spirit of GovHack for amazing team work	July 2016
o NIWA Proactive Communicator	February 2016
o Organized two Jenkins meetups in Sao Paulo, Brazil	2012 and 2013

### **Education**

o BSc Information Systems, Mackenzie University

August 2003 – July 2007

# **Training**

o Vue 3 + Typescript. Vue Mastery. Online.	2021
o <i>Pandas.</i> Kaggle. Online (Kaggle).	2020
o Intro to Machine Learning. Kaggle. Online (Kaggle).	2020
o Building Web Applications in R with Shiny. DataCamp. Online.	2018
o OWASP NZ Day Advanced Web Hacking and Secure Coding. University of Auckland. Auckland	, New
Zealand.	2017
o AWS Concepts. Linux Academy. Online.	2016
o Apache Spark Essentials. Linux Academy. Online.	2016
o Web Development with Servlets and JSP. Sun Microsystems. Sao Paulo, Brazil.	2007
o COBIT and Sarbanes-Oxley. Claro. Sao Paulo, Brazil.	2006
o Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate career. Bras e Figueiredo. Sao Paulo, Brazil.	2003

## **Experience**

Research Software Engineer, NIWA

October 2018 – Today

- Working remotely from Auckland on Cylc using Python Tornado and JavaScript Vue.js.

Java Engineer, NIWA

Jun 2017 - Sep 2018

- Java **JEE** development for EcoConnect.

o Full Stack Software Developer, Spark Ventures

Oct 2016 - Jun 2017

- **AWS** development, build systems, and Java development using **SpringBoot**.

Software Developer / Operations, N/WA

Apr 2015 - Sep 2016

- Configuration management, automation, Java development, CI and DevOps pipelines.

o **Senior Big Data Engineer**, Boa Vista Servicos (Equifax)

Jun 2014 - Mar 2015

- Impala, HDFS, **Hadoop**. Cobol and Java development. Creation of business cases for execute and management teams.

o Senior Software Architect, Tokio Marine

Jan 2013 - May 2014

 ActiveMQ cluster, internal workshops and trainings, internal web services, SSO, integration of new Portal with Liferay. Company-wide KPI monitoring implementation.

o Senior Infrastructure Engineer, Tokio Marine

Oct 2012 - Dec 2013

Automation with Jenkins and Puppet.

o Senior Software Engineer, Tokio Marine

Oct 2011 - Sep 2012

- Java web development with Servlets, Portlets, and **LifeRay** modules. SSO with **OpenAM**, QA environment with **Jenkins**, Ivy, and other tools.

Senior System Analyst, Lojas Riachuelo

Jul 2011 - Sep 2011

- Java Swing development for retail POS system.

o Senior Software Quality Engineer, Vivo (Telefonica)

Jan 2010 - Jun 2011

CRM development with Java and GWT. QA pipeline set up with Hudson, Sonar, Testlink, FishEye, and JIRA.

o Senior Software Engineer, Nossa Caixa Bank

Apr 2008 – Dec 2009

 - .NET C# and Java support development. Integration with Mainframes using Cobol, MQSeries, DirectConnect, Uniface, and Java in Z/OS Linux.

o Junior System Analyst, Claro

Jun 2007 - Mar 2008

- Java web development and J2EE using Servlets, EJBs, JMS.

o Junior System Technician, Claro

Jan 2006 - May 2007

- **Java Swing** and J2EE.

o Value Added Services intern, Claro

Jul 2004 - Dec 2005

- VAS middleware systems, billing integration, Java development on HP-UX and Solaris.

#### Certifications

o gvSIG User Certificate	2018
o LFCE Linux Foundation Certified Engineer	2015
o Professional Scrum Master I (scrum.org)	2011
o ISTQB CTFL Certified Tester	2010
o SCWCD Sun Certified Web Component Developer	2009
o ITIL Foundation V2	2009
o COBIT Foundation V4.1	2009
o SCJP Sun Certified Java Programmer	2006
o MCP Microsoft Certified Professional Windows 2000	2003